（パイロット）「よくも　セーンを！」
来るなー！
うわっ!!
うっ…　うわぁぁぁぁ！
セーン少尉が
バックラッシュで損傷です！
（ローワン）いったい
何が起こったんだ？
≪（管制官）メディック！
３２２号機　大破。　緊急ベイルアウト。→
（集）ハァ…　ハァ…
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
♪♪～
Medic!
Serious damage to Unit 322! Emergency bailout!
Second Lieutenant Saen
was injured in the backlash!
What... the hell just happened?
How dare you do that to Saen!
Stay away!
So, everything that makes me whole
I'll now give to you
I'm yours
Say, there's lots of happiness
in this world, isn't there?
Someday, if we're together
Even if someone calls you a liar
And tries to hurt you with heartless words
Even if the world tries to make
you wear a crown of thorns
Without even trying to believe in you
I can take your side, and yours alone
I know that solitude, that pain
So, everything that makes me whole
I'll now give to you
the fit
（四分儀）あれが
ヴォイドの力ですか。
So that's the power of a Void?
Now, Oogumo.
（涯）大雲。　今だ。
Yes, Commander.
（大雲）イエス　コマンダー！
うっ…。
♪♪～
（パイロット）うっ！
ハッ。　いのりさん…。
Inori...
Wake up!
しっかりして！　いのりさん！
Inori!
♪♪～
What was that?
何なんだ…。
「桜満　集」
えっ？
Shu Ouma.
「１５秒やる。
いのりを回収して離脱しろ」
I'll give you fifteen seconds.
Recover Inori and get out of there.
H-Huh?!
え…　えっ！？
Tsugumi! Where's my next target?
（綾瀬）「鶫！　次のターゲットは？」
Direction: ten o'clock. Distance: 400!
（鶫）１０時の方向に　距離４００！
Too far away! Don't you have a closer one?
（綾瀬）「遠過ぎ！
もっと近いのは？」
Withdraw if you don't like it!
You're working too hard, Aya!
なら　引いてよ！
綾姉　頑張り過ぎ！
その子　もう限界だよ！
Your poor craft's had about all it can take!
あん？
But I want to do all I can...!
（綾瀬）「でも　できるだけ…」
（綾瀬）あっ。
（ダリル）♪♪「フッフフ～ン」
Hey, a short and stocky one.
Glad I rushed over here!
（ダリル）「何か
ずんぐりしたやつがいる」→
「急いで来て　よかった！」
（銃声）
（綾瀬）「速い！」
He's fast!
（銃声）
（綾瀬）あっ　あぁ…！
あっ！　ベイルアウト！
Bailout!
（ダリル）「あれ？　悲鳴は？」→
Huh? Where's the screaming?
「な～んだ　つまんないの」
Aw, man.
That's just no fun.
（綾瀬）ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
（グエン）何！？
これを歩兵がやったというのか！？
What? You're telling me a foot soldier did this?!
（ローワン）「戦闘記録映像が乱れていて判然としませんが　おそらく…」
The battle footage is too distorted
to say for sure, but I believe so, Sir...
（グエン）対　エンドレイヴ用の
個人兵装だと！？
A personal anti-Endlave weapon?!
Like I can report that to the higher-ups!
こんなもの報告できるか！
≪（ダリル）
ダリル・ヤン少尉　入ります。
Second Lieutenant Daryl Yan entering.
切れ。
Turn it off.
これは　これは　ようこそ
ダリル少尉。
My goodness, Lieutenant Yan! Welcome!
ヤン少将のご子息自ら→
To think the Major General's own son
would honor our mobile cockpit with a visit!
移動コックピットで
臨場してくるとは→
You certainly live up to your
reputation for bravery and hard work.
さすが　勇名に恥じぬ働きぶりだ。
Are you here on your father's orders?
ここには　お父上の命令で？
（ダリル）いえ　自分の独断です。
No, I came on my own initiative.
I heard the report that a battle had started
新型エンドレイヴを
オペセンに搬入する途中で→
just as I was bringing a new-model
Endlave to the operations center...
戦闘が始まったという知らせを
聞いちゃったので　思わず！
...and I couldn't stop myself!
なるほど。　では　ありがたく
力を貸してもらおうか。→
I see. Well, then, we'll be
glad to have you help, Lieutenant.
少尉！
Don't joke with me.
冗談は　やめてよ。→
You want me to touch that fatty flesh?!
僕に　その脂身に触れっていうの！？（グエン）はっ？
I'll do as I please, got it?
いい？　僕は自分の好きにやる。
And if you get in my way...
もし　邪魔したら
パパに言い付けるからね。
...I'll tell Papa on you.
フフフ。
くそがきめが…！
That shitty little brat!
捜索範囲を広げろ！
Expand the search area!
Capture and interrogate everyone...
女　子供だろうが
端から捕らえて尋問しろ！！
Women, children, everyone!
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
あの…。
（着信音）
Um...
（綾瀬）「すみません　涯」
綾瀬か。　状況を。
I'm sorry, Gai.
Ah, Ayase. Report your status.
（綾瀬）機体を失いました。
申し訳ありません　私の責任です。
I lost my craft.
I apologize. It's my responsibility.
I see.
「そうか。　確かに残念だな」
Yes, that is a shame.
「俺は　君に　あの旧型で→
I gave you the cruel order to
hold your position for eighteen minutes
１８分間　持ちこたえるという
過酷な命令をし→
in that old-model Endlave,
and you rose to that task.
君は　それに応えた」
「だというのに
君は　自分の責任だという」
And yet you claim responsibility...
「つまり
俺は指揮官失格ということか」
I suppose that means I'm not a fit commander?
ち…　違います！
それは　私が失敗したからであって。
N-No! It happened because of my failure! I...
その…。
「冗談だ」
I'm kidding.
「君が無事でよかった　綾瀬」
I'm glad you're all right, Ayase.
≪（鶫）綾姉の心拍数
絶賛上昇中！
And Aya's heartbeat soars
to the top of the charts!
黙んなさいよ　鶫！
Shut up, Tsugumi!
あの…　それで…。
Um, so...
Are you awake now?
目が覚めたか。
あっ。　いのりさん…。
Inori.
Gai... did I get the job done?
（いのり）涯。
私　ちゃんと　できた？
No. I'm disappointed in you, Inori.
いや…。
お前には失望した　いのり。
あの…！
Um!
ちょっと
ひどいんじゃないですか？
Aren't you being a little mean?
I'm sorry to butt in, but...
口挟むのも何ですけど…。
She worked really hard!
And she even got badly hurt for...
彼女　すごく頑張ってた！
ひどいケガまでして…。
知っている。
I know.
結果が全てだ。　あいつは　最後に
大きな　へまをした。
Results are everything.
She screwed up big-time in the endgame.
"Screwed up"? How?
へま…。　いったい何を？
お前に
ヴォイドゲノムを使わせたことだ。
She let you use the Void Genom.
あのシリンダー？
That cylinder?
あれは　本来
俺が使うはずのものだった。
That was supposed to be for my use.
お前に預けたシリンダーは→
The cylinder she gave you contained
one of only three enhanced genoms
セフィラゲノミクスが　３基のみ
培養に成功した強化ゲノムだった。
that Sephirah Genomics
has successfully cultivated.
使用者に付与される力は
王の能力。
The power it bestows on
its user is the king's power.
王の能力？
"The king's power"?
ヒトゲノムの
イントロンコードを解析し→
It can analyze intron
sequences in the human genom
and draw out the power hidden
within them by converting it into Voids.
その内に隠された力を→
ヴォイドに換えて
引き出すことができる。
What's a Void?
ヴォイドって？
形相を獲得したイデア。
An idea which has acquired form.
The sword you used was one.
お前が使った　あの剣のことだ。
That was Inori's Void.
あれは　いのりのヴォイド。
Different Voids can be
extracted from different people.
別の人間からは
また別のヴォイドが取り出せる。
神の領域を暴く
ヴォイドテクノロジーの頂点。
Void technology trespasses
into the realm of the gods,
and what you obtained today
is its crowning achievement.
それが　お前の手にしたものだ。
You are no longer allowed
to powerlessly stand still
もう　昨日までのお前のように→
無力に立ち止まり
命を見過ごすことは許されない。
and turn a blind eye to others' lives like before.
お前にも戦ってもらう。
そんな…！　いきなり？
You'll fight with us.
But... you can't just suddenly!
覚えておけ　桜満　集。
Remember this, Shu Ouma:
この先　お前が選べる道は
２つしかない。
there are only two paths you can choose.
黙って　世界に淘汰されるか
適応して　自分が変わるかだ。
You can sit quietly and be selected out of
this world, or you can adapt and change!
うっ…。
（着信音）
どうした？
What is it?
Things have gone sour, Gai.
（アルゴ）
「ヤベえことになったぞ　涯」→
「１４区画の地下駐車場に
白服どもが突入しやがった」
The damn whitecoats have stormed
the underground parking lot in Area 14.
「地下駐車場？」
The underground parking lot?
Yeah. Somebody said it was safe,
（アルゴ）ああ。
誰かが安全だって言いだして→
and then the close to 100 people
taking shelter there got caught all at once.
避難してた１００人近くが
一気に捕まっちまった。→
それに　綾瀬を食った新型は
皆殺しのダリルだ。
On top of that, the new-model
unit that took down Ayase
belonged to Kill-'em-All Daryl.
ちょっと　めんどくせえぞ。
That makes things a little tricky.
Daryl... ah, the Kaleidoscope, eh?
ダリル…。　あの万華鏡か。
Gai, this is an unexpected predicament.
（四分儀）涯。　不測の事態です。
現時点での戦力差を鑑みるに→
Given the current difference
between our fighting power and theirs,
a rescue mission isn't worth the risk.
救出はリスクに見合いません。
撤退を進言します。
I recommend we pull out.
No, we can't pass this up.
いや　見過ごせないな。
これは不測じゃない。　天佑さ。
This isn't a "predicament." This is providence.
全メンバーに告げる。
Attention all members:
We are about to exterminate the Anti Bodies
and rescue the residents of the fort!
われわれは
これより　アンチボディズを殲滅。
フォートの住民を救出する！
えっ…。
Furthermore, this operation won't be
a covert one like the ones so far.
なお　本作戦は　これまでのように
隠密作戦ではない。
As of this moment,
現時刻をもち　われわれ　葬儀社は
その存在を世界に公表する。
the Funeral Parlor is making
its existence known to the world!
存分に働け！
So work with all you've got!
Aye-aye!
アイアーイ！
（一同）おー！
（アルゴ）よっしゃ！
All right!
（一同の歓声）
Only you. All right, I'll knock out a script.
さすがですね。
シナリオを飛ばしますか。
ただ　少し急ぎ過ぎでは？
But are you sure this isn't a bit too soon?
返事は　どうした？
Where's your answer?
≪（殴る音）
It's pointless to resist!
（兵士）無駄な抵抗を…！
Spill it. Who's your leader?!
吐け！
リーダーは誰だ？　言え！！
Tell me!
《特殊ウイルス災害対策局
通称　アンチボディズ》→
The Special Virus Disaster Response Bureau,
commonly known as the "Anti Bodies."
They can unilaterally
designate people as symptomatic,
《独自に感染者を認定でき→
その判断に基づいて　感染者を
処分する権限が与えられている》
and have been granted
the authority to dispose of them
based on that judgment.
（女性）やめてください！
夫が何をしたっていうんですか！
Please, don't!
What is it you think my husband's done?!
Mama, potty!
（りょう）ママ　しっこ。
Wait just a second, Ryo.
ちょっと待ってね　りょうちゃん。
その人　病気じゃありません！
お願いします！
- He isn't sick!
- Mama!
Please!
切ない光景だね。→
What a heartrending sight... My heart quavers.
胸が震えるよ。
Officer!
軍人さん！
I'm begging you, please spare him!
お願いです　助けてください！
What do you think you're doing, you filthy hag?!
何すんだ　くそババア！！
（女性）キャー！
菌が　うつるだろうがぁ！！
最悪だよ！
You'll infect me!
- That would suck! How dare you?!
- The cornerstone of GHQ's
public security operations...
《ＧＨＱの治安維持の要
最凶最悪の牙》
their cruelest, sharpest fang.
《それが
今　俺たちが戦っている敵なんだ》
That's the enemy we're fighting right now.
フン！　構わん　やりたまえ。→
No matter. Just do it.
やつらを殺せ！
Kill them!
≪（りょう）ママ～！　ママ～！
Mama! Mama! Mama!
（ダリル）まったく！　母親とか→
Ugh, this "mother" crap...
たかが産んだくらいで
うっとうしいんだよ。
No need to be so annoying just
because you gave birth to him.
This can't be real.
嘘だろ…。
Alpha Team, are you in position?
≪（鶫）「アルファチーム　配置は？」≪（アルゴ）「まだだ」
Not yet.
≪（鶫）「急いで！」
≪（アルゴ）「分かってる」
Hurry up!
I know!
（銃声）
（ダリル）フゥ～！
あっ！
涯！
Gai!
Begin the operation!
作戦開始！
≪（レーダー手）ミサイル接近！
Missiles incoming!
Intercept them!
迎撃するんだ！
（グエン）葬儀社か…。→
The Funeral Parlor, eh?
絶対に逃すな！
Don't you dare let them go!
フフフフ。→
Now for some action!
来た　来た。
It's started...
始まった…。
Listen up, Shu.
《いいか？　集》
《アルファチームが
遠距離攻撃後→
After Alpha Team's long-range attack,
エンドレイヴを
可能な限り　敵陣から引き離す》
we'll draw the Endlaves as far
out of enemy camp as possible.
And once we've drawn them the preset distance,
《そして　設定した距離まで
引き離した後→
チャーリーチームが動く》
Charlie Team will make its move.
[無線]（鶫）ポイント　レッド
ブルー　イエロー　制圧完了。→
Points Red, Blue, and Yellow now in our control.
Distance to planned point: seven!
予定距離まで　あと７。
Now take good care of my babies, Aya!
綾姉。　うちの子たち　よろしく。
（綾瀬）「任せて」
Leave them to me.
♪♪～
（ダリル）「アハハハ。
ほらほら！　踏んじゃうよ！」
Uh-oh, I'm gonna step on you!
[無線]（鶫）目標　Ｄラインに到達。
Target has reached D-line!
（ダリル）「ゲームオーバーだ！」
It's game... over!
Now!
今だ！
[無線]（通信手）中止！　攻撃中止！
Abort! Abort your attack!
（ダリル）「はぁ！？」
Excuse me?!
We have multiple missiles locked on!
How are there too many for us to intercept?!
（副官）ミサイル　ロックオン多数。
迎撃可能数を超えているだと！！
[無線]（四分儀）
ＧＨＱ　アンチボディズ→
A word of advice to Major Guin,
commander of GHQ's Anti Bodies Squadron Three.
第３中隊長である
グエン少佐に勧告します。
オープンチャンネルです！
He's on an open channel!
We are the Funeral Parlor.
Release your hostages and surrender.
[無線]（四分儀）われわれは葬儀社。
人質を解放し　降伏しなさい。→
受け入れるなら
命までは取りません。
If you agree, we will spare your lives.
少佐殿　どうなさいますか？
What now, Major?
フン。　切り札は　こちらにある。
We're the ones holding the trump card.
テロリストども！→
Listen up, terrorists! We never bow to terrorism.
われわれは　絶対に
テロには屈しない！→
貴様らが
これ以上　抵抗するなら→
If you continue to resist, we'll set off
the gas we planted underground.
地下に仕掛けたガスを
作動させるぞ。→
If you don't want that, show yourselves!
そうされたくなければ
出てこい。→
"Funeral Parlor," is that
what you called yourselves?
葬儀社とか言ったか？→
I assume even you must have a leader? A leader!
君らにも　リーダーがおろう？
リーダーが！
I'm the leader.
≪リーダーは俺だ。
≪（足音）
（グエン）葬儀社とは
また　不吉な名だな。
"Funeral Parlor" is quite
the sinister name, isn't it?
世界は　常に選択を迫る。
The world always forces
a choice on its inhabitants.
適者生存。
それが　この世界のことわりだ。
"Survival of the fittest":
that is the law this world operates by.
俺たちは　淘汰される者に
葬送の歌を送り続ける。
We continue to offer funeral
songs to the ones selected out.
Hence "Funeral Parlor."
故に　葬儀社。
The name signifies that we
are always on the singing side...
その名は　俺たちが
常に　送る側であること→
生き残り続ける存在であることを
示す！
that we are the survivors!
Evidently you don't understand your position here.
（グエン）
立場が分からんようだな。→
今　淘汰されようとしているのは
いったい　どちらか…。
Just which one of us
is about to be "selected out"?
貴様たちが盗み出した
遺伝子兵器はどうした！？→
Where's the genetic weapon your people stole?
吐け！！
Confess!
そんな話　初めて聞いたね。
Well, that's the first I've heard about that.
（グエン）１０　数えるまで待つ！→
I'll give you a count of ten to tell us.
その間に言わねば
貴様は蜂の巣だ！
Then we'll shoot you full of holes.
時間どおりよ。
Right on schedule.
Wow... It's all going right according to his plan.
すごい！
全部　あいつの作戦どおりに…。
《これで　俺が失敗したら
みんな…》
Now if I mess up, everyone will...
Believe.
信じて。
You can do it. For sure.
できる　絶対に。
Because I... belong to you now.
私は　もう→
あなたのものだから…。
（グエン）１０！→
Ten!
９！→
Nine!
Eight!
８！
だぁぁぁ！！
Seven!
（グエン）７！
（ダリル）あっ！
Six!
（グエン）６！
（ダリル）ぐあっ！！
（グエン）５！
Five!
４！→
Four!
３！
ぐぁぁぁ！！
Three!
Two!
（グエン）２！
行け　万華鏡！
Go, Kaleidoscope!
One!
（グエン）１！　時間だ！
Time's up!
何！？
What?!
うっ！
（爆発音）
♪♪～
♪ Blooming wildflower ♪
♪♪「咲いた　野の花よ」
♪ I beg you, please tell me ♪
♪♪「ああ　どうか　おしえておくれ」
♪♪「人は　何故…」
♪ Why do people fight and hurt each other? ♪
よくやったな。
Good work.
You overcame one of your own limits today.
今日　お前は
一つ　自分自身を超えた。
That's something you can be proud of.
それは　誇っていいことだ。
♪♪～
Come with us, Shu.
来い　集。
俺たちと共に。
お前には
やれることがあるはずだ。
I know there's something you can do.
♪♪～
I wonder...
《あのとき→
あそこで
あいつの手を取っていたら→
What would have happened
if I'd taken his hand then?
どうなっていたんだろう》
《でも　これでいいんだ》
But I made the right choice.
《あれは　きっと
生涯で　一度きりの冒険》
That had to have been
a once-in-a-lifetime adventure.
《今日からは
また　日常が始まるんだ…》
Today my everyday life starts up again.
（教師）それから　今日は　もう１つ。このクラスに転入生があります。→
Okay, one last thing.
Our class has a new transfer student. Come on in!
入って。
≪（ドアの開く音）
≪（生徒）うお　女子！
≪（生徒）へえ。　カワイイじゃん。
A girl!
Hey, she's cute!
（教師）楪　いのり君だ。
This is Inori Yuzuriha.
≪（椅子を引く音）
嘘…　でしょ？
This... can't be real...
ホントだよ。
Of course it is.
I'll never be loved by you again
♪♪～
Or needed by you again, either
And so here I am, all alone
What did you say that day?
Words that'll never be heard flutter in the air
Even though I know better,
I can't help making another
Hopeless wish today
Keep holding my hand tight and don't let go
Tell me you'll stay with me
Your hand in mine was warm and kind